

【(+1) 514-562-7368 | ■ liubingyuan1988@gmail.com | ★ by-liu.github.io

## Summary \_\_\_

I am a Research Associate at École de technologie supérieure (ETS), Canada. My research interests include deep learning, computer vision, and medical imaging. I have well-balanced academia and industry experience for more than 10 years, with 10+ published papers in the related conferences and journals, e.g., CVPR, CVIU, ACCV, etc, and experience of designing and developing enterprise-level applications, such as image retrieval, optical character recognition (OCR) and recommendation system.

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_

### École de technologie supérieure (ETS)

Montreal, Canada

RESEARCH ASSOCIATE

Nov. 2020 - Present

- Research interests include deep learning, computer vision, and medical imaging.
- · Responsible for providing deep learning based solutions of eye disease screening for our industrial partner, Diagnos, Inc.
- Working with Prof. Ismail Ben Ayed and Prof. Jose Dolz.

Coohom, Inc. Hangzhou, China

ALGORITHM EXPERT (TECH LEAD OF COMPUTER VISION TEAM)

May. 2018 - Mar. 2020

- Lead the computer vision team, responsible for research and development of computer vision applied in the interior design domain.
- Responsible for the perception system of KuAiDesign, an AI assisted 3D interior design product.

Qihoo 360, Co. Ltd.

Beijing, China

MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER

Aug. 2017 - Apr. 2018

• Responsible for recommendation algorithms applied in Huajiao (a live streaming app).

Alibaba Group, Inc.

Hangzhou, China

SENIOR ALGORITHM ENGINEER

Apr. 2016 - Aug. 2017

- Responsible for optical character recognition (OCR) applied in parsing business license, business card, bank card, etc.
- Responsible for object detection algorithms provided on the machine learning platform on Alibaba Cloud.

### Huawei Technologies, Co. Ltd.

Nanjing, China

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jul. 2015 - Apr. 2016

• Responsible for applied machine learning, supporting applications in business partners like China Mobile.

### **Education**

#### **Institute of Automation, Chinese Academy of Sciences**

Beijing, China

Ph.D. IN MACHINE LEARNING

Sep. 2010 - Jun. 2015

- Supervisors : Prof. Hanqing Lu and Prof. Jing Liu
- Got the national scholarship awarded to the top 1% students.

# Zhejiang University

Hangzhou, China

B.S. IN INFORMATION SCIENCE AND COMMUNICATION ENGINEERING

Sep. 2006 - Jul. 2010

- Rank: 25/210 GPA: 4.29/5.0
- Excellent graduate award

# **Selected Publications**

- Bingyuan Liu, Ismail Ben Ayed, Adrian Galdran, Jose Dolz: The Devil is in the Margin: Margin-based Label Smoothing for Network Calibration. CVPR, 2022.
- Bingyuan Liu, Christian Desrosiers, Ismail Ben Ayed, Jose Dolz: Mixed-supervised segmentation: Confidence maximization helps knowledge distillation. arxiv, 2021. (Major revision in MedIA)
- Bingyuan Liu, Jose Dolz, Adrian Galdran, Riadh Kobbi, Ismail Ben Ayed: The hidden label-marginal biases of segmentation losses. arxiv, 2021. (under review)
- Bingyuan Liu, Jiantao Zhang, Xiaoting Zhang, Wei Zhang, Chuanhui Yu, Yuan Zhou: Furnishing Your Room by What You See: An End-to-End Furniture Set Retrieval Framework with Rich Annotated Benchmark Dataset. arXiv, 2019.
- Bingyuan Liu, Jing Liu, Jinqiao Wang, Hanqing Lu: Learning a Representative and Discriminative Part Model with Deep Convolutional Features for Scene Recognition. ACCV, 2014.